[Music]
این مغازه‌ای که می‌خواییم بریم قدم بزنیمin ast hossein ma
و واقعا به شما پیشنهاد میکنم که فقط
دوربین رو کنارتون طوری نگه دارید که انگار
خاموشه. اونها خیلی درباره
it's off they're very strict about no
سیاست دوربین ممنوع سخت گیرن. خیلی شلوغه. قطعه ها را
camera policy it's so busy plow the
برای بازسازی مجدد یا بازیافت شخم میزنن
parts re-manufactured recycle some are
بعضی ها جدید هستند و برخی تقلبی‌اند. باتری های جایگزین
new some are fake replacement batteries
??و صفحات نمایش برای تبلت های سامسونگ. قاب
and screens for Samsung tablets backings
برای تبلت های سامسونگ. بعدش آنجا
for Samsung tablets then you see back
یک صندوق بزرگ برای ایمن نگه داشتن
over there see those big chest escapes
را می‌بینید - تماما پول نقد - اگر
over there all cash you want to buy
،یک قابی برای آیفون‌تان می‌خواهید تا مثل یک جدیدش را بفروشید
cases for your iPhone to sell like new
می‌توانید جعبه های خالی بخرید، این ها
you can buy empty boxes these are just
.فقط جعبه های خالی‌اند که دارن فروخته میشن
empty boxes they're selling so this
یک خانمی دارد آیفون 5 مدل سی را می فروشد
woman is selling iPhone 5c so they're
آنها جدید نیستند اما معتبرند. آنها استفاده شده
not new but authentic the reviewed and
و بازیافت شده‌اند. یک فرد دیگری اینجا به طور عادی
recycled another guy here swapping out
.قطعات را تعویض می‌کند
parts casually
- هر وسیله‌ای که برای تعمیر گوشی‌ها نیاز دارید
all the tools you need to repair phones
- ‌مانند محفظه‌های خلاء، سیم‌چین‌ها
like the vacuum chambers the wire
برای جدا کردن صفحات - گیره‌ها
cutters to remove the screens jigs to
تا مثلا همه چیز را یکجا
like hold everything in place in the
-در تراز صفحه نگه دارد. باز کردن؟؟
lineup the screens the incessant
مداوم چسب بسته بندی، این یه نشانه‌ای از
cracking of packing tape that's the sign
،بسته شدن معامله است. بعدش هم از اینجا سر در می‌آورید
of a deal closed and then you pop out
در حومه شهر، به حومه شهر
here in a suburbia welcome to the
!خوش آمدید. اوه خدای من! من عاشق شینگن هستم
suburbs oh my gosh you can't talk bad
نمی‌توانی درباره شینگن صحبت کنی. شینگن از یک
about such a Schengen started from a
روستای ماهیگیری شروع شد با 300,000
fishing village from 300,000 to 10
تا 10 میلیون، 2 میلیون، 20 میلیون
million or 2 million 20 million no
هیچ شهری در تاریخ تمدن بشری
cities in the history of humans as a fan
.تا جاییکه ما می‌دانیم، توانایی انجام چنین کاری را نداشت
3 know who is able to do this shrink
away from with Google to tree on pole
want to show you a cool photo room I'm
gonna put you the fool who did you can't
go
شینگن دارد -
look I found certain is creating more
میلیاردر های بیشتری از شهرهای دیگر
billionaires than any other cities in
،در چین تولید می‌کند. منظورم این است که آنها هرکاری می‌توانند انجام بدهند
China I mean they can do everything the
بازسازی دنیا که ؟؟؟؟؟؟؟؟
factory of the world that foal doesn't
،این را نمی‌فهمند. این میتونه اروپا
understand this it could be Europe the
ایالات متحده یا هرجای دیگری. شما تقریبا نه ماه از ما
u.s. anywhere else.you about nine months
.از ما عقب هستید زمانیکه تکنولوژی در میان باشد
behind us when you have technology that
- و این تنها یک حقیقت است. الگویی که در
just affect the model that has been
- شینگن توسعه یافته است در واقع می‌تواند
developed issue John can actually be
- خیلی ترسناک باشد برای الگوهایی که
quite frightening for models that had
- قبلا تثبیت شده‌اند و در نواحی دیگری
already been established and very
.از دنیا موفق بوده‌اند
successful in other
- من فکر می‌کنم که
the words I do think that the core
،هسته‌ی عقیده به اشتراک گذاشتن آیپی
tenants of sharing IP that they have is
.این است که آنها بسیار فعالند. این یک تغییر فرهنگی است
extremely enabled it's a cultural change
یک مدتی طول می‌کشد، اما آینده
it would take a while but the future is
ممکن است. این "سیلیکون ولی" نیست که
possible it's not that Silicon Valley
-از تکنولوژی جدا شده است، آنها بسیار
got divorced from technology they're
-به تکنولوژی علاقه مندند. آنها فقط
very much about technology they're just
-به بالا رفتن از بلندی‌ها ادامه دادند و نکته کلیدی که
kept moving up the stack in the key
،منجر به این شد از نظر من
thing that drove that in my opinion was
قانون موریس" بود. قانون موریس از"
Moore's law Moore's law is named after
گوردون مور" نام‌گذاری شده است که یکی از موسسان"
Gordon Moore who was one of the founders
-اینتل" بود و حول و حوش 1960 او با یک"
of Intel and in like 1960s he came out
-کاغذ ظاهر شد. او پیش‌بینی کرد که
with a paper he predicted that every two
،گمان می‌کنم هر دو سال
years I believe it was the number of
-تعداد اجزایی که می‌توانند در یک تکه سیلیکون
components to get fit and the same piece
.با اندازه‌ مشابه جا گیرد، دو برابر می‌شود
of silicon would double and so in one
بنابراین در طی یک سال، شما می‌توانید 10 ترانزیستور را
year you could fit ten transistors in
.در آن جا دهید، در طی دو سال برای مثال می‌توانید 20 تا را جا دهید
here to use they're gonna be like 20
-سپس 40 تا و با گذشت یک دهه
then 40 a decade on you're talking about
.صحبت از میلیون‌ها و میلیارد‌هاست
like millions and then billions imagine
-تصور کنید شما یک پرینتر دارید و دارید
you have a printer and your printing
صفحات را پرینت می‌گیرید، شما می‌خواهید بهینه‌تر باشید
pages and you want to be more efficient
خب شما از فونت با اندازه 12 به -
well you go from a 12-point font to a
فونت با اندازه 6.5 می‌روید.  دوبرابر کاراکترهایی که
6.5 getting twice as many characters in
در یک صفحه هست، شما دارید دو برابر
one page and you're getting twice as
.اطلاعات را از پرینترتان دریافت می‌کنید، همه دریک مرتبه
much information on your printer all in
این عینا همه‌ی آن چیزیست که
one go and that's literally all Moore's
قانون موریس بوده است. همان کاهش دادن سایز فونت
law has been is reducing the font size
مدارها. در دهه‌های 70 و 80
of circuits in the 70s and 80s there are
-بسیاری از تحقیقات شکست خورده وجود داشته که تلاش کردند
many failed research attempts to build
.تا کامپیوترهای موازی بسازند
parallel computers by computers that
"کامپیوترهایی  همانند "کری ماشین‌ها
were like you know the Cray machines and
-و ماشین‌های متفکر، 60هزار
the Thinking Machines sixty thousand
پردازنده، مقیاس های بزرگ و چیزی که شما-
processors and scale up and what you
-فهمیدید این بود که اگر شما بیشتر از
found was that if you spent more than
-دو سال فرصت تحقیقات را بگذرانید تا تلاش کنید و
two years of research time to try and
،کارایی کامپیوترتان را دوبرابر کنید
double the performance your computer it
-این بسیار ارزان‌تر از آن بود که یک‌جا بنشینید
was by far cheaper just to sit back and
-و منتظر بمانید تا افرادی از اینتل تنها قانون موریس
wait and let guys like Intel just move
-را پیش رو بگذارند و سریعترین پردازنده
Moore's law ahead and buy the next
-بعدی را بخرند و چیزی که شما فهمیدید
fastest processor and so what you found
این بود که در واقع پی سخت‌افزار بودن
was that actually being in hardware
سودآور نیست و
wasn't profitable
-بنابراین چیزی که واقعا در آن زمان فروش محصولات را برگرداند
and so what really sold products back in
.امکانات بودند
the day was features well one of the
خب یکی از چیز‌هایی که شما می‌توانید با ویندوز 98 انجام بدهید مشابه چیزی است که
things you can do with Windows 98 it's
-در وب است، شما می‌توانید در هارد
similar to the web you can navigate on
درایوتان با استفاده از دکمه‌های
your hard drive using the backwards and
-عقب و جلو بگردید همانطور که می‌توان
forwards buttons just like we would on
.در وب اینکار را می‌کنیم
the web the first generation of Windows
that would come out and a new generation
would be so slow it'd be completely
unusable and then two years later I go
it's actually kind of okay and then four
years later it's like zipping along it's
not because Microsoft made it faster the
computers got faster for free and so
people are able to now not have to worry
about writing detailed stuff in C code
they could use high-level languages
they're able to use like web pages and
in JavaScript comes along and with all
of that sort of fervor going on and
people chasing that innovation there was
no value in soldering parts it really
wasn't in 1983 worldwide sales of
personal computers increased 76 percent
but last year the increase was only 19%
and this year analysts predicted sales
growth will flow to about 4% losses
among the two largest home computer
makers through June of this year
surpassed 600 million dollars in that
building of stuff had to go to an
economy where people were paid a lot
less and what you see is now that
Silicon Valley whole tech ecosystem is
served like driven as far as the road
goes and now Moore's law sort of end is
ending or ended and the car is still
kind of gliding off the cliff right but
there's no more road underneath it in
there like huh like computers just
aren't getting that much faster anymore
and so now you're seeing people going
through a phase of optimization which is
great but at the same time people are
like ok well how do we differentiate my
product right like optimization sucks
it's not a great business model is now
we have super computers in our pocket
now the question is what do we do with
it right and what does that thing in my
pocket or not I already do and so people
are realizing there's niche markets
hardware we need to have a small
accessory you're gonna have like my
Fitbit all these little things my little
digital locks my smartphone's my sensor
networks the IOT sort of stuff coming up
and they say great we need to figure out
how to build this and now they're coming
back to this ecosystem I mean oh you
guys know how to solder we forgot about
that
that's really good can you help us build
these things what you always say when I
was 18 the first time I go to the US I
use a trash can and I got wood vacuum
cleaner till the very first day of our
robot well you want a robot that's just
like you are slightly better so you
always feel challenged I dropped out
from the university after first year of
college decided to go for this path and
its really nice to be in hacks because
hexes are the best educator and help you
girl
hexxus a hardware accelerator the
world's first hardware accelerator we
take teams that come in with a proven
technology and a prototype and help them
to get ready for market launch we
provide 100 thousand US dollars we help
them with electrical engineering design
for manufacture industrial design
mechanical engineering their market
strategy how they're going to launch and
for that we take nine percent equity and
in the startups
I'm Thomas co-founder of Provenza and
add Herman so we make a big robot we use
a kind of special joystick it's usually
used in surgery these things
it's a force-feedback joystick the the
market that we targeted the one of
nuclear decommissioning and what you can
see here is a small version of a robot
and now our hacks we are building the
very big version so you can compare the
wheel size that will be something quite
huge the bigger version of the robot we
transport a robotic arm to automate some
of the part of the the commissioning
work engines as as everybody now knows
the hardware capital of the world right
so this has been our home ever since the
starts the reason we can come here and
take the teams here is because of the
ecosystem around which helps them to
build products really fast and from
initial concept all the way up to final
product release into the market Noah is
a headphone company we're making the
world's first tunable headphones they
work out how you hear and provide the
perfect music for you so I can show you
here the hearing profiles of my
colleague Luke and my hearing profile
what you can see is that there is this
difference at certain frequencies
between the way that Luke is sensitive
to that particular note or sound the way
that I'm sensitive to it what our
headphones do is sonically mold the
sound and make sure that what we hear is
not too bassy it's not too trebly it
sounds balanced it sounds even and it
sounds the way that it was recorded
anybody who's going through a certain
development
they're better off doing it here because
they can get things made so much quicker
and so much cheaper I mean you know you
try doing something like that in the UK
and take you around a month typically to
make something which is specialists from
an engineering firm here you can do in a
couple of days let's say we completely
design a new robot we can get it out
pretty much in a week even if there's
ten parts we can send it out or we can
do it ourselves so you get ten sweetie
printers a print at the same time and
you get all the parts put it together in
this fire
I never seen any parallel thing like
that when we were in States for for some
of the Senate ports we can order in the
morning and then we get it in the
afternoon or the day after we can get
manufactured parts and in a few days in
Switzerland we were planning to do this
robot in nine months and here we have
the opportunity to make it in in three
months so it's really a race if you look
back through the years I obviously
shinjang became a manufacturing hub very
very quickly and not that long ago was
literally rice paddies
academic wise and in popular media it's
usually summarizing one sentence which
is that shinjin was a small sleeping
fishing village and then because it was
designated as a special economic zone it
became a metropolis overnight that
singular sentence is what I'm trying to
demystify through my work today exactly
how many people lives in Shenzhen is a
mystery the number ten million is used
more as a reference so from three
hundred thousand to ten million and this
population grows no cities in the
history of human civilizations we know
that was able to do this prior to 1980s
China was in a very poor economic state
there was a stagnation of Industry there
was a plant economy no one was allowed
to own business it was a very poor
country the leaders in Beijing have been
thinking about what can they do to try
to lead the country out of poverty don't
refer to another power damage engineer
sort of entities losses on the food are
encouraged in disagreement we know donor
[Music]
you don't wanna do
viola concert sitting under Shah Shuja
Angelica shank on a bender to commercial
the you to be Jonathan doing spirit I
take a commission for village huh taken
a user community to one generating
option side Canadians over furniture to
fail when he push a button laa-laa
Zoe mama yo Jordan gardens of Heligan
clever they set up the for special
economic zones each of them next to a
already developed economy the ambition
was simply what can the country do to
generate jobs to generate economy to
feed the people essentially was a very
actually modest intention under the plan
economy that was a social safety net
every person was rationed with food
coupons clothing coupons electricity
coupons
it was only in Shenzhen you can buy a
piece of bread with money to be willing
to come to change into this economic
zone to try to create something else it
attracted people who wanted to have more
freedom general optional shirt on
shuttle you cocoon Tom was hunting was
hunting a Night at the top turn of joy
to return to the corner to our cheer
someone some cute attention is so cool
nia-malika fighting
you will send an English dub you know
some use of native Egyptian dr. tehrany
something you would know is selection
so to Danika pinguin the content
J trash actionability ha ha muji
volatile fatty tomorrow could play with
jinguk ivanovitch and creamy hot ahuna
sit on shark barrage here tell order got
one column and she hotel regretfully the
pin brie our forests and our country's
food that has to be an engineer cheerful
Tricia to return for the uncooked Oh
mayor Eugene providers engine attrition
Alinea so it'll work - in Libya sentient
from gulag
ok so check out shangri-la 3-1 Tracey of
years for the water to cook wash it with
your changing what to me was remarkable
about engine is
even the planners themselves would tell
you that the city evolved in a way much
bigger and faster than they would have
predicted I think it's it's overly
generous thing that shinden was nothing
and then with this set up special
economic zone suddenly it became a city
it didn't there is something else that's
not answered simply by top-down planning
[Music]
yes sir good morning thank you all for
joining me in a discussion about
innovation that is happening right here
in China we're investing with you the
developer community we have been
investing in open source solutions
because we know that when there are
standards and when there are open source
offerings that the pace of technology
innovation and the pace of technology
adoption accelerates I think for the
past hundred years the Industrial
Revolution put us into more cages
consumerism has cubed a lot of
creativity but for the post-industrial
generation they should have more freedom
to create to explore to invent I things
to make a movement about bringing air
back so we're here with the MakerBot
cupcake C&C which is a 3d printer you
can build things like Thom Yorke's head
because he actually open sourced the
data that was filmed for a video of his
now what's also interesting about this
whole scenario is that there's a whole
thriving community of users who are
taking these to build all kinds of
different objects they're sharing the
objects online and additionally they're
sharing information on how to build and
upon the design everything is completely
open sourced the software's open-source
the hardware is open-source I just can't
wait to see what people come up with I
think the recent emerging of the maker
movement pretty much started around 2003
2004 in the US laser cutting and 3d
printing is helping people to be able to
build stuff and as you beautiful fun
rather than just having business workers
right around that x guy named Dale
Dougherty he was thinking about starting
a publication called make before make
came out the only word we had was a
hacker right and I think he didn't want
to call them are using hack because it
had a really negative connotation at the
time and make was sort of the thing you
would type to compile a program so it
would resonate well with programmers and
maker was like serve the demonym of
people who would read the magazine
that's sort of coined the turn maker I
think in clean up publication he sort of
solidified the movement in the Maker
Faire created that phenomenon
[Music]
in China in beginning new partners bar
makers do bar cared about makeup on
because we're gonna make fierce in
Europe in the area where circulars so
instead of waiting for someone to do
that we say why don't we do it when they
told me they were gonna bring the first
maker fair here I was like how do you
have a maker fair in a area where people
don't make for a recreational thing they
do it for a job right you know cuz
making in the West is something that
you're using to remind people who are in
service economies that there's a thing
called manufacturing right when you have
a manufacturing economy you want to
remind them of this manufacturing that
seems weird and what I realized is that
actually China's middle classes aside
the entire United States population so
even if a small section Chinese people
had risen to the upper middle class it's
big enough to create a movement in China
itself compared to the United States
scale making
we don't know it's going to be
successful or not the first year we have
over 60 makers and NASA we have over 200
makers it's a huge number some
interesting phenomena are also emerging
out of this in the past years what's
happening is the open source hardware
movement traditionally the second
poorest coast and proprietary you need
to have a contract and non-disclosure
and a huge sum of prepayment in order to
get access but with open source how
where everybody can access to that
information and everybody can modify
that to suit any people here they create
a circuit board and the just under
expectation it is going to be open it's
going to be copy and evolved by someone
else there's no one running around in
Shenzhen say okay well I should be
creative for creating this if someone
else can make this get someone else to
use it
marietta better not having the Eagle
attached to our creations and understand
how actually open-source system works
the maker movement is at that junctures
I'm getting a little sick of hearing
about the same people on TV over and
over and over again so I decided to do
something about it this Arduino project
which I called the enough already will
mute the TV anytime any of these
overexposed personalities is mentioned
to mute the TV I'm gonna use an IR LED
now any time a keyword is mentioned the
TV will mute for 30 seconds our
producers caught up with Kim Kardashian
earlier today it should do a pretty good
job of protecting our ears from having
to hear about the details of Kim
Kardashian's wedding
arduino is becoming the trigger point
because it has too many minions of
makers are using that arm for their
people have talkies and diseases and
stable if we come to shenzhen like 10
years ago 20 years ago it will be very
difficult for a maker to tap into
resources but now you have so many
resources it's in the middle of our
reforming so the big company especially
the silicon providers like Intel like a
male like TI's you look at that oh we
have new customers we have a new
possibility for new future applications
of where our technologies so they makes
their own controller board like Edison a
Curie so they want to tap into the early
stage of the development of the
applications now this port is based on
the Intel technology so it's tiny
dual-core computer system it has two
Wi-Fi Bluetooth and it is also it's
around a Linux operating system on it I
think part of the reason Intel's having
to sort of turn that way they know their
road map as well as anyone else does
they kind of define Moore's law and they
saw the bridge go out and from
underneath them before anyone else did
they've managed to drive technology like
this and then the other founders like
TSM see and you see of Austria behind
but now that's slowing down everyone's
catching up they're like oh god we're
looking for air and trying to find a
place to move and so they've struggled
to keep up with the phenomenon they
created they haven't made headway into
mobile and those are the most ubiquitous
computer today they're missing on a huge
market opportunity and so it's the
extent that they're trying to figure out
how to adapt their innovation model to
something more flexible and so they
really want to make sure the Intel brand
is in front of the youth to make sure
that they remember that Intel is
actually like a thing that they want to
design with later on and not just you
know something out of reach
we have tried to introduce it to nine
years old this is a little bit difficult
but is acceptable you do not need to
write any boring code in a smart note
you can just drag and drop and the link
them together what they're doing is
they're learning how to code on a
computer translate that into hardware
and they'll build a project on our laser
cutter or a 3d printer for something to
accept a stimulus light motion or sound
and then output some result
last year one kid built a key reminder
for his mom so that when she left the
house a motion sensor would pick up her
movement and say hey don't forget the
cue and it's kind of funny to hear that
a eight-year-old will know whether he
wants to be doing mechanical circuits or
just a purely software experience
so that's enter level and then would
give them more systematic introduction
to how to build I have the skews off you
go you can't use the makerspace to
create whatever you want you are genius
you are young inventors I've seen some
great examples of open-source hardware
being used to actually make a difference
and create a better world
the difficulty is monetizing that
because I do believe that business
solves a lot of the world's problems and
people need to be able to make money if
you're providing value to the world
which is making a world a better place
then there should be compensation for
that in 2010 I started the first
makerspace in China Kosh intogen I can
invite a lot to give a talk about open
source our the first question always
come up on people's mind is how do you
protect your intellectual property and
how can you make money if you don't
protect your intellectual property I got
that question in Shanghai I got a
question in Beijing I got that question
everywhere I go but when I give the same
talking center the reaction I card is so
what's new about this we've been making
money on this for 20 years
[Music]
geot for insurance shows to each other
UNCG energy Santee Tony Romo hero Arlo
general pop I thought you turned into by
auditors who I said
[Music]
the reason we're here in much fun pay is
literally because of the Optronics
markets you know it's a fantastic
resource of all different possible
components and different devices which
can kind of be Frankenstein together to
make prototypes both teams it's a source
of inspiration it's a source of
discovery of new products that could
potentially be taken to the west like I
see every month of different invention
down there but nine times out of ten
they're probably not gonna make it to
the west but some of them do chicken and
I've got a zombie the twenty more sugar
three tickets you young ladies from the
UK online now so she can champion oh she
gonna walk when she saw the even farm
Enda how do don't you wander you
mouthwash I mean I don't need the show
how again zero shows you need a little
how many Dodson had pull it off the pie
you can get a little bit of feel here
what's even upstream of what's gonna hit
the tacky United States you see a couple
things popping up here they're a little
shop well right oh well pop out no we're
selling these things and heard it before
like the hoverboards we're here a couple
years before they hit the United States
and then you eventually sort of see them
hit the states and other countries Chile
sweet you party on base facility for
surely don't think you got a song here
John
sorry Thomas all the time since 2003
similar to volatility to show you go see
us and see Santi show liquor logical
Chile's your to Santiago the thing
there's a number of different ways to
sort of look at the market for an
engineer you're sort of limited it's
thumbing through catalogs and looking at
pictures and very slowly going through
specification sheets for examples if you
want to put a switch in a product if you
want to know how it feels you want to
kind of know the exact size and the
little mountings and the fussy bits and
it can take a long time to find exactly
the right part become here and there
like stalls with like hundreds of
different types and you can just reach
in and just touch them and play with
them and can like what stall by stall
and see all the different variety and
it's not there it's not just a showroom
if once you find this which you like you
can be like highlight by
thousand of them and then for very
little price so you can just over the
kind of buy it carry it off and you know
go into production
you can fix your phone here Kodama
triggers a woman okay I'll call the
daughter
okay yeah Lisa Lillien
Tydeus variously as yo mama
it's got a huge amount of acquired
knowledge and skills there's electrical
engineers there who solder up 50 PCBs
for you in record time you can go down
there and piece together different
components to make a new mobile phone
there's nowhere else in the world you
can do that
you know you can get like a chipset that
was in a notebook for example you know
less than $15 which can enable computing
power in sell a new product that's you
know fantastic resource for some
startups that kind of philosophy is kind
of spread out around China
Carmen Sally me and Amador Yugoslavia
totally worth friends how much help was
the end of a relationship Connor and her
movie you go and touch it - you go poof
anaconda leave I go Pompano cumin Yogi's
hetalia IOT - so it's awsome kauri okay
Pacheco time zero ha ha ha John Boehner
yo Tarrant olive oil
shorty yo there are no tidal wave ha she
was champion Chanchala yo Darren and
cover my so it hamid rezian's change
across all the currency so you know
Jelena
Todd Shin Chon vaya con champion Chris
Young soo Jeong Seon ho ba da ba da da
da sangria - idea that her chose I quote
each own child whom the Harlem area near
the shazier the photometer South Korea
even Superman comic I just really love
it love it I this one here Joe Tom allow
it is my interest you at home sure Joe
you're serious it actually talked up the
whole Hollywood that Cody
what is your hula jihad and willing by
the kite uncle Chi to make us appear so
in a Commodore t-shirt if you can just
shuffle spiritual either emotion when we
starting to look at the maker coming to
send then that's this excitement and how
open their system is like nowhere else
you can buy all sort of stuff everything
is available the embody find in the West
there's a binary distinction between the
makers and the Howard startup the maker
you do this for fun you do is for your
passions but when you're starting to
make this into a business you should
forget about sharing you should forget
about all this open stuff and focusing
on the business but in here
that's very little differentiations
between I want to make this for fun and
I want to make this for profit
there's no binary division of the
mindset of makers versus startup make a
start-up in China it's a continuum
you shouldn't been stopped from making
money out of the thing you love to do
and you should not be forced to choose
between open and proprietary just
because you want to become a business
why now it's just in the West
we haven't seen open source our system
working generating was a logo sure
jealousy so that our total agenda she
more younger johanna
comiendo went to heaven familia kids
what about you anymore young people now
the second coalition iphone have my own
that allowed this year please enjoy the
EP eventually campaña de mañana
first you should have the chill on your
top social to tell you more yonder i've
also
Laura don't you know that you can either
chunk of intelligent way
[Music]
in the West is an idea that I can have a
company that produces nothing it has a
ton of patents but produces money by
suing everyone for rights those patents
do you even have inventors you have
lawyers making money off of buying
intellectual property and trading it
that's weird right it's kind of weird
that you produce nothing but make a lot
of money the idea that you can take an
idea in a world that's this big and say
exactly one person owns the right to it
globally like Apple has the right to the
phone with rounded rectangles they're
the only people who can produce that
really like seriously this is the word
we're gonna live in like we just give
people monopolies through the IP system
for 20 years for stupid ideas because
they were first-to-file
that made sense back in the day when
there were fewer people less innovators
a less connected world now we have like
this network of people were like we're
empowered to do our things and we can
almost trade our creativity and China's
ecosystem it is this network ecosystem
of an idea for an idea like let's let's
trade now you realize your place in
ecosystems I need other people around me
you can't be a dick to like all the
other guys around you just because you
have a monopoly on this thing someday
you're going to be on the bottom side of
the chain and you're going to need other
people's help and so you build networks
of collaborations with people by sharing
in this open source philosophy
oh yeah we have all first copycat let's
say it's a plan so but yeah reverse
engineer from the video of the all the
hardware companies that come in here of
course we encourage them to pass on all
of their technology but we don't expect
them to fight anybody who's copying them
we expect them to be moving much faster
than anybody who's copying them and
coming up with the next thing the whole
time and building a brand and eventually
those patents may get used when they get
into a patent trade off that's the use
of patents not not not to stop people
copying you the way to stop people
copying is to make whatever they're
copying irrelevant because you've come
up with something much better a huge
barrier I think to small companies the
United States is like the patent system
in the copyrights and just like left and
right as legal challenges and you spend
a huge portion of your money on lawyers
and IP filings and all it sort of stuff
it it's a drag it really is if you want
to be making stuff you want to be
actually working with people and sharing
ideas openly and getting things going hi
I'm Shane I like to do many things
this one's called a solo week you
control speed by indeed this is my laser
beam isn't it's called a cover tracks
yeah the whole board story is a very
interesting example of somebody in
America who came up with the
intellectual property and then spent a
long time fighting manufacturers who
were actually creating something which
was similar that's a great example of a
case where I would have encouraged
somebody not to start like fighting
around IP protection it's better just to
build a brand around a really great
product make sure you've got you know
the leading product in the area this is
really the first time we have a
technology product which become widely
popular which
I'm a cultural icon pack we don't have a
name for it it just emerged more people
come in the Bob wait we get the Bobby
tricking eventually you will get to a
form which will go viral this is kind of
point to the future of how things could
happen
so in Horsham Bay you still find some
cheddar biscuit fakes there are
reproductions of established brands I'll
give you an example because this is a a
contemporary sort of Shan Zhai Matt
watch running on an Android system the
reproductions were really the items that
were sought after by people who could
not afford the the real thing
my understanding is that the early Shan
Zhai were people who worked for the
bigger corporations here like Nokia
Motorolla Foxconn and they were some
very smart engineers who got sick of the
management and I like look I can build a
phone cheaper better faster than these
guys can I understand why I have all
this process I can make it for half the
price if we just cut cut the fat and
they would quit talk to their friends
who they knew all this upstream
suppliers and they would get the other
parts and they would build you know what
we're effectively you know copycat
phones the key innovations are able to
do it much much lower cost just you know
learning how to walk before they could
run essentially the most similar things
to the ideas of Santa in the West it's
the idea of Robin Hood they try to
empower the poor with the latest
advancement in technology since I and
the maker movement startups yeah Freya
like they are very much share the same
spirit even the DNI from becoming a they
feel powerful when they talk about
people who left the factories incopy the
phone well that was kind of like the
open source stuff that was an open
source they just sort of like oh the
schematics are in the desk I will
community help myself to them make a
photocopy and then leave the factory
with it right you know was that stealing
or was it open source right in in the
West it's called theft right out here
it's called sharing so the device is
that there's a hall from the market and
you can see it has a number of markings
on it this one was the the higher grade
version it was 70 80 bucks u.s. when you
power it on you see that it's running a
a very well skin flavor of Android
iconography is actually pretty good and
then the great thing is this one
supports two SIM cards replaceable
memory card and a replaceable battery
batteries which is actually a feature
that many local people really want to
have there they're unhappy about a
having no memory card slot and B having
not a replaceable battery the companies
were able to access very easily the two
basic components that you need to make a
phone one is the boom ban which is
basically a twin tip circuit boards and
the other one is the Gumo which is
basically the shell so there were
companies specialising in making boom
bang and boom all that had slots for
those printed circuit boards that were
very easily accessible by the companies
you know people from the West who are
used to sort of month-long development
cycles like how do I do this is amazing
like this capability came out of nowhere
overnight but actually it's been honed
over like a decade or two out of those
roots of people you know coming out of
the big factories and figuring this all
out themselves
Shandra a sample that is still going on
now but it is a very small percentage of
what is produced in the market there is
a very strong emerging middle class in
China that has the purchase power to
afford the original items that may be
more extensive than being reproductions
it is not possible to target new markets
just with imitating the established
brands there is a limit to what can be
achieved in that sense once they kind of
got in a position where they could now
build a copy of a phone pretty well they
can now start innovating they'll take
like an Android phone an iPhone and mash
them together and come up with this
weird thing that is pretty cool and it's
different in some way you know if you go
in in the market in question but you
will find there many people distributing
this type of advertisements for company
that are called white brand companies
that will make it for you assembling
very very different components and that
you can add your your own
your name or whatever you want and
distribute it as your own item yeah
these are these are all white label
ideas it's an empty sample and all these
are different empty samples so they can
go ahead and build it for you on the
spot and then order I don't know however
many you want and later you can actually
ask them to go ahead and put your
graphic on the front you know for
example or maybe you know these logos
over here in the West kind of philosophy
is are we come up with something really
fantastically new that nobody's done
before become the market leader and
we're really successful the Chinese
mentality is slightly different they
look at something that's already on the
market and then they create a much
better version of it much quicker it's
not copying its evolution of products
which becomes much better than what was
out there before we've grabbed another
one in the market there looks like a
SmartWatch but you'll notice that I only
has a single button and the graphics are
made for children so this is a phone
plus GPS module that you can use to sort
of report a kid's location if the kid is
in trouble they can dial their parents
you can see it has like SOS call
features I would bet that probably 80 to
90% of the design material in here is
borrowed from other vendors who use
these previously and other SmartWatch
designs but people are sharing the IEP
the guy who probably shared the IEP to
them was someone who could sell them
chips or motherboards of circuit boards
and so there was some factory backing up
that sharing crosses they want people to
use these things and that lets these
guys try try try like this what many
models of this in fact when we're buying
this as a woman next to us was asking
for these and then left on the table we
said this one's too thick let's go find
one that's that's that's thinner than
this one over here they'll probably have
less features or less battery life or
whatever it is but the market here can
build these different variants and
service it gives of the phenomenal
ecosystem
[Music]
something is really happening companies
are realizing the importance of having
new ideas and being different so many
companies who were involved in the
Shanghai before are now looking at
design they're now looking at how to
develop innovation in their own
companies the model that has been
developed in Shenzhen can actually be
quite frightening in other parts of the
world and it's not surprising that many
American companies are now looking at
models that are developed in China to
see how they can adjust themselves well
Suzy a huge kudos in the C to the
together MCMC the immersive
to the University
she can tell you our chunji but don't
eat cereal mine
super intuitive the who isn't into me
Musha 5re rely suit I'm Molly
[Music]
the OPM will show you in charge
champagne so far should see each I
actually good he goes on Sunday you're
trying from the OEM OPM will move from
erosion so same you got chimed in
attention chanting in Chinese hi I'm
John here that we see but they're not a
man you're not just wondering you're
okay amateur don't try anymore
about flight up so those are son of a
product that we make this is President
Obama wearing my headphone with my
business partner Mitch Richmond this
peoples be here you know a car what I
hear but Justin's picture my partner
Venus Brown this year's signed by
lavina's Brown what I am I forgot who
signs this there's somebody famous I
forgot this is my office
and that's something I can live without
it's my sink or like I can't do
without my cigar sorry I just cuz we are
not your traditional I can manufacture
right which is you know give me a
product to manufacture we manufacture
some like a monster and all that a
Harman Kardon creative out a classy JBL
all the biggest industry we actually
dominate anywhere between an eight to 12
percent of the US market audio side but
what we're doing so different is we we
have our own these I house we're able to
create some really cool incredible
product so here's like design house some
inspiration about what we can do we have
like some instruments 3d printing rapid
prototyping these team is designing some
characters in 3d this is a game it's
interactive learning
in China a lot of factories are very
traditional so this is also very a new
model the CEO he tried to drag this
model and since since 2005 they are
producing now for 45 brands
mostly international and mostly in u.s.
come on sit down Allah Allah Allah
Arlene Cellini Electric which is yeah
show-cell McConnell shillelagh delegate
equipping sound in second out ping Chang
Lee near on woody Korean dr. Cathy
entirety power through the engine total
not dumping talent this hydrogen public
entanglement redecorate humble Solanco
matter medicine sure you know most
people don't realize that there's at
least twenty six percent of the
technology from Silicon Valley actually
converse in jail so what they do is they
hire kind of like a headhunter so to
speak because there's so much innovation
we are about minimum of a month to a
year events when it comes of technology
for example we have made this incredible
bed you can sleep on there and the
moment you wake up in the morning you'll
give you stats how many tell you roll
over how much Steven how much rest you
and then also can treat your blood
pressure
you gotta tell you you have any problems
we identify and this is technology
existing range today and we've done this
almost two years ago
number one the way life is routine how a
computer there should be a tissue should
be a submissive on nightly the human
thinking how how would you on the
typical careers unceasing legal when do
the kissing people making I don't try
anything we say like 25 percent of
innovation creating engines and are by
by the American say by it go to us and
then they sell it here 100 time more
expensive china feel little bit bored i
think about this business model we made
it here but all the credit is are is for
some some somebody else in only no
central pins here
- Savion till you who are partially due
to the RC function she go in only know
you from thank him Papa Union he playing
hey tinkle everybody is looking for the
Chinese startup made in China
want the proof to show to the world like
look we innovate we have a lot of
opportunity here
I think all focus should be let's create
a quality product and you can be proud
and say this is made in China so if you
can just focus on that new technology to
focus on a branding and to focus on
equality and I think with the next five
year people have different perspective
of made in China I think that will
happen
sorry amigo sure wish I wanted her
stranger you can take a co-founder
syndrome are to go so you go to your
shitty I thought you go are you sure
doctor even go to tell Papa to show
you're cool quarter room I mean footy
the fufu she's in Krakow - we come
here centre so she ended up we achieve
career to go toggle flip 6 B or D de
she's a commercial bank oh yeah Simula
are done in a pattern of children to
attend a meal in a routine to drink oh
come in the room tributary being a
champion who tree being our machine sir
Center reports Allah percentage they are
kind of tissue healing tea new partner
toting what has happened in Shenzhen
within 35 years of time its uniqueness
is fading because those same innovation
say policy innovation or industry
innovation now it's everywhere in China
so it doesn't have that edge of being
the only one or even the first one
anymore it's kind of a catch-22 right it
recognizes what it has been able to
achieve but it's also inherent like how
are you gonna make it better
[Music]
people who come to sunshine get older
and as the experience grows the start to
develop something near as a
manufacturing they become engineers
become brands
meanwhile the the government is pushing
out manufacturing to the out Syria of
shangela
[Music]
it's a logistical it IPC the whole of
Ottawa tongue gotta get down shinsen she
call that the intensity and the density
share the GDP insanity Gianola we may of
Sudan Richard II by house but with an
impact incidents and God feels amazing
modules and he thought you're meeting
from that you to the Cayenne or social
network UPI or maybe at that time a lot
of Confucians is happening right now
what I'm going to do what's next
should I invest in branding or I just
cause my company I think it's a perfect
moment for innovations because I can
attract at least our portion of them to
put the resources to innovate something
new path to do yoga gotten good at art
often a good job or team she had a
potential signs that touches opportunity
of art also cheated on him to the
Neptune high doesn't change a woman
tried to decide to enter the East Asian
that's how he can play some piss on that
Charlie learn just how I roll now at a
time at Express tiny pizza Hamish is on
my education credit or Souta ah Jia Jia
Jia you Jia see Gokaiger innocent yet
Costra poco so it supported the American
even Rangoon soon until sook Irina and
your Anisha to Sakai vida loca little
Clinton to the cute little concoction
Estonia most resistant to the King gourd
into song emoji or the know what you are
a woman I've seen a change in the way
the innovation in China happen
this fantastic number of Chinese
startups the doing really really good
products Chinese thought ups are getting
better because they want to learn from
Europe if you go to a conference with
innovation speakers from from France or
from Germany or from England or whatever
most of the people with the Chinese in
the room so want to learn
Konoha or some tricky technology to you
to test intelligential sincerity in
Genova true what is and what is center
level quadrant can purchase exactness
Antonio Meucci
or John Cochran Santa Anita yonder she
Santa possess or ego pans
Santa si Jin sir sans I see two genes
talkin PhD defend audience tell Hannah
although it is that what you wanted to
achieve in the past twenty years
everybody who wants to make in a Silicon
Valley has to go through this very tight
and small selection process by a small
group of people who what a venture
capitalist young white males between
twenty to thirty controlling how
technology orbit about how technology
will be a-prime and how technology will
be available to the general public that
is the very definition of control
economy they're ready to have like these
massive settlement fights and epic legal
battles I call their Supreme Court and
stuff like that
if everyone were like you know actually
we all do good job let's just work and
try to figure out how to innovate but
it's a matter of getting critical mass
of people to buy into it without a big
brain dictating what kind of feature we
can have the Sun die system is catering
to everybody's name it's not a small
group of people who determine I guess
develop when and how
right now we are still at a very early
stage of this open source how our
movement if we trace back to the lane ID
the open source software test has
started I mean Bill Gates was speaking
publicly about how open source is
communism and it won't destroy the
software industry and hey today
Microsoft is one of the most supportive
of open source and even open up the
entire Windows 10 if the history of open
source software excuse as a benchmark we
are pretty much five years away from
this being discussed in mainstream it's
a mindset change but the future is
possible
and they talk about you know China's
authoritarian there's strong rules and
all sorts of stuff people here have
developed a way to coexist with the rule
of law and the way life needs to run
this sort of looked the other way at the
right times I think when things need to
happen this is how we've managed to make
sure that everyone gets fairly
compensated everyone's fairly rewarded
and it works through this system there
another thing to be clear as a thirteen
doesn't mean evil right it's just that
there is one authority I mean the
Communist Party knows as well as anyone
else that they have to keep the people
happy they're not just going to like
kick people around because they want to
and they want to be trivial and small
about it so they try really hard to put
economic policy in place that brings
prosperity one of the things that the
government has said is we need a service
economy that's tech oriented and we need
to get more young people interested in
this the maker movement we want to graph
that into our system and hopefully
inspire another generation of young
people to want to become you know
hard-working factory owners and
employers and innovators like their
parents were and and now there's even
like little maker spaces in cafes and
innovation labs like popping up left and
right
[Music]
sayonara to whatever su chio show me is
enough
Yamaha cholo quanzhou cuddly toy item
chilli chilli in a you go Louie in de
Indias so technically under chilli usual
high in dialect Roma cafe in body a
llama copy image trauma confessions I
truly enjoy earthen
ocean and natural psycho Japan polio
punctual in church and IDO Johanna
Norman hi Eden a teenage audiences I
imagine a cheetah
Alan Union the couch Antonio can enter
treatment Ronnie event entrancing
Giuliana John food I food truncation
watch a quiet Cholula - so Jody and
Sango ye robot Chantal o I prefer the
term fertilization Josh Rene Mouton
seokjeong core components what a dollar
on one hand it's great that the national
government have seen this emergence of
new media new technology and I think
it's genuine to want to support it
however I don't think there's a very
good track record so far of governmental
involvement in these more bottom-up
activities we take for example art
districts something that was emerging
out of China 1020 years ago that really
caught the imagination of artists
colonies galleries but as soon as the
government and started to support it the
inevitable process of gentrification
happened rent went up more notable
galleries moved in so the artists who
really were trying to experiment had to
move out so I have a concern along
similar lines for these tech sectors the
government in trying to support it
inevitably will formalize it
[Music]
it's interesting to sort of see the city
evolve and so there's a sort of wave of
money and gentrification you can sort of
rolling from the you know from the east
to the west and from the south to the
north the pace at which they do is just
crazy you can walk from one end of the
state to the other and by the time you
walk back the other side enough to say
will change you you won't recognize it
it's just it's just tearing itself down
and rebuilding itself as you walk
through it there's a region over there
that was all these electronic shops they
just leveled it put up a luxury mall and
put a high-rise on top of it and you
wouldn't recognize it I mean we have
more high-rise here - anyway in a world
I mean honestly if you walk around
Center right now we have over two
hundred seventy eight buildings being
built up to 74 I travel all over the
world and we look everyone else I hate
you know we are the fastest growing you
know society rather industry today
that's just a fact
in China there is a general lack of
awareness of the negative ramifications
of gentrification just as you know in
the 60s nowhere New York thought that
was a bad thing the reason why the city
has embraced this notion new technology
is trying to reinvent itself
my concern is that industry invention it
wants to very quickly rid of its even
immediate past a city that really
struggled really was dependent on a lot
of things the government couldn't
provide things happen by chance
accidentally a lot of it was bottom-up
in fact there was not one fishing
village there were 2,000
[Music]
these villages have evolved along with
the city they have taking up very
important roles in providing housing
providing a certain social structure
jobs a certain stability to the city
that was not planned
they simply evolved was the formal city
I would like it more like a you know
sort of the bacterial colony as a petri
dish eventually you grow a lawn of
bacteria across it you know all the
communities become interconnected but
you know that that's sort of a natural
growth curve
[Music]
we are in by Sciuto which is one of the
300 more than 300 of em village in
Shenzhen and here like no matter what
you don't need to go anywhere and you
can find everything here that's the
amazing part of this it provides
everything you need for a community when
the government designated engine as a
special economic zone they left patches
of land for the villagers themselves to
build homes this is a boundary line
between the city and the urban village
this side is open oh man and this is
urban village owned these urban villages
are also breeding ground for a lot of
innovation you can change a structure
you can change the facade you can spill
your workshop into the alleyways the
whole neighborhood was built in this
kind of bottom-up way Shenzhen really
represents a new modern image it's a
modern city it's a new city the urban
villages complete opposites to that
image the mayor's office declared the
necessity to rid the cancers of the
society in those words
I should Joe is going to be redevelops
this months actually April 2016 so this
is how fast 150,000 people's who lives
here needs to be relocated this there's
some rumors that like the market here is
eventually going to have to be displaced
because as as things gentrify the rent
on the shops are going to go up to the
point where they can't sustain selling
these like small parts and whatnot just
across the street there's much more
urban village going on that's we're
headed to and I can't say if it's for
better for worse but it's definitely
things are changing and so you train
this and straight out of like the market
into you know urban village area like
this personally I have a bias I hope
that it never goes away because I enjoy
it so much and it's such a valuable
resource to me you'll see big districts
where people are taking phones and
tearing them apart and then another area
putting them together into another phone
of sort of recycling and upcycling going
on so you can see like down there
there's a person here with a what looks
like a pile of trash but if you look
closely it's just that they're going
through mobile phones and stripping out
parts from them
it's like shucking corn almost
let's take a quick walk through one of
these informal areas
my phone cycle parts he actually has big
bundles of other boards that he's pulled
out of phones that were previously
thrown away and then what they do is
they they take out the motherboards and
they take the chips off and eventually
find their way back down the market you
can get your like roast pigs feet and
then iPhone cases this market itself
plays a kind of a critical part in the
ecosystem in terms of being able to move
goods around you know if one factory did
a build and they had some excess and
they want to get rid of it a lot of it
will come through this market and get
recycled through the system this one
some straight from the factory floor you
can see that the motherboards are even
still in the the carrier so this one was
one they didn't pass out of Apple fully
fabricated and it found its way into
scrap heap here well people will go
ahead and they'll you in really see
they've pulled off some ICS
for recycling and reprocessing into
fixing phone and so forth and here's uh
these here are blank motherboards and
the interesting your mother's you see
like no solder on and all they still
have a gold color which means that
there's been no processing of the board
at all it's straight virgin boards from
the facility you're gonna move on we're
getting a crowd I can get plenty of
useful stuff for a fraction of the price
that you would have to even in the
markets you know on the Main Street
that's the stuff that's going away that
those guys will innovate no matter what
they innovated despite the government
right they'll be they'll be they'll but
they'll keep walking and they may have
cut a path that looked interesting and
that path is now being paved into the
road they'll cut another path you you
you've never had a fox run over by a
steamroller when they're when they're
putting a road over a forest the Fox
know how to move away right can it can
run and find out that place and as long
as there's continues to be green fields
for these people to go to I think I
think things will be okay and and
demilitarizing the the Western IP
ecosystem would be great right I think
that's something we can do right but
it's just as hard as bringing us back
from the brink of the Cold War everyone
has to sort of ease off universally
agree that we need to have a new
paradigm and I think one of the problems
in doing that is that the militarization
of IP has really benefited big companies
and if they back off their stance of
having huge caches of IP to nuke the
little companies that come up they're
threatened by innovation and so instead
of seeing like this openness come out
you're seeing exactly the opposite
you're seeing the system calcifying and
maybe will happen and is like you know
sure they'll own their edifice but you
know they'll become so entrenched that
they can't move on right the each of
them is locked in their space and then a
very flexible ecosystem like China will
just roll over them later on and they'll
wonder how that happened
it's because they did it to themselves
at the end the day
the beautifulness of standings who come
here with the talents with your efforts
that your diligence you can earn a place
for yourself that makers the our startup
the Internet of Things producing how're
they all converge here in center and
that's what makes sense and the second
body of power not into Putin's to the
game palette yeah what Shenzhen Santa
kundi and Ania that oxygen food that
harsh with energy free roaming yes in
the tofu
Sandra and Tino Rodriguez in Doha traigo
yo yo yo yo seen the live stream you one
more drive each other oh now you look at
this light switch ad astray every five
star hotel every way in China right now
this is a proper girl identified this is
a perfect sample if we can just have a
person take 2-3 second to just make that
adjustment
China will be a perfect place detail are
they going to be more like the UK in the
sense that they'll just shed the
manufacturing background as they
gentrify and and sort of just go
straight for like you know a service
economy or will they keep rooted in a
sort of a manufacturing ecosystem and
keep designed parallel to it or will
they just forever stay in manufacturing
right is that really just their their
core base and value and wit and where
they want to be
I mean if China went from where they
were to where they are today in 30 years
they could do that again 30 years ago
thin my life that we could see the
incidence question it'll be interesting
to see where the answer ends up
[Music]
[Laughter]